Any change in the patient's condition?
‫أمن تغيّر طرأ على حالة المريض؟‬
No, but…
‫لا ولكن…‬
What's his BP and pulse?
‫ما معدل ضغط دمه ونبضه؟‬
Dr. Tenma, what about Mayor Roedecker's operation?
‫ماذا عن عملية المحافظ "روديكر"‬ ‫يا د. "تينما"؟‬
Let's begin the surgery.
‫لنبدأ الجراحة.‬
Oh… Yes, sir.
‫حسنًا يا سيدي.‬
Oh, right. What's this patient's name?
‫صحيح، ما اسم المريض؟‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
What's this boy's name?
‫ما اسم الصبي؟‬
Well…
‫في الواقع…‬
I see… We don't even know his name.
‫مفهوم… لا نعرف اسمه حتى.‬
It'll be fine. Hang in there.
‫ستنجو. اصمد.‬
I'll save you.
‫سأنقذك.‬
Kill him…
‫اقتليه…‬
Those kids… Those twins, they're nowhere to be found!
‫الولدان… التوأم، نعجز عن إيجادهما.‬
Did you look hard?
‫هل بحثت جيدًا؟‬
Of course, I did! I've looked everywhere!
‫بالطبع! بحثت عنهما في كل مكان!‬
Maybe they're playing hide-and-seek somewhere.
‫لعلّهما يلعبان الغميضة في مكان ما.‬
"Maybe they're playing hide-and-seek somewhere," huh?
‫"لعلّهما يلعبان الغميضة في مكان ما."‬
Fraidy-cat Tenma!
‫"تينما" المرتعب!‬
Fraidy-cat Tenma! Wuss!
‫"تينما" المرتعب! يا ضعيف!‬
Hiding won't do you any good, fraidy-cat Tenma!
‫لن يفيدك الاختباء يا "تينما" المرتعب!‬
If you hide too long, you'll pee your pants again.
‫إن بقيت مختبئًا لوقت طويل‬ ‫فستتبول على نفسك مجددًا.‬
You boys! It's getting late! You can't play forever!
‫يا أولاد! تأخر الوقت!‬ ‫لن يسعكم اللعب إلى الأبد!‬
-Okay!
‫حسنًا!‬
-See you tomorrow! -Later!
‫- نراك لاحقًا!‬ ‫- مع السلامة!‬
Bye.
‫مع السلامة.‬
-Bye!
‫- إلى اللقاء!‬ ‫- مع السلامة!‬
What about me?
‫ماذا عني؟‬
Hey, you guys. I'm over here.
‫يا رفاق. أنا هنا.‬
Come find me too!
‫ابحثوا عني أنا أيضًا.‬
I'm over here!
‫أنا هنا!‬
Come find me!
‫ابحثوا عني!‬
"Fraidy-cat Tenma," huh?
‫"تينما" المرتعب؟‬
What would you like to do?
‫ما الذي تود فعله؟‬
That man who came by this evening is still at the front gate.
‫ذلك الرجل الذي أتي الليلة‬ ‫لا يزال عند البوابة الأمامية.‬
Who is he?
‫من يكون؟‬
He was the psychiatrist of Richard Braun, that detective we once hired.
‫كان الطبيب النفسي لـ"ريتشارد براون"،‬ ‫المحقق الذي استعنا بخدماته ذات مرة.‬
I'll chase him off.
‫سأبعده.‬
Karl.
‫"كارل".‬
I can't see well anymore. Tell me what he's like.
‫ما عدت قادرًا على الرؤية. هلّا تصفه لي.‬
Yes, sir.
‫حاضر يا سيدي.‬
He's an older man.
‫إنه رجل مسنّ.‬
What do you think of him?
‫ما رأيك فيه؟‬
He doesn't seem like a bad person.
‫لا يبدو لي رجلًا سيئًا.‬
He also appears to be quite desperate.
‫ويبدو بائسًا أيضًا.‬
I see.
‫فهمت.‬
I appreciate that you have agreed to meet with me, Mr. Schuwald.
‫أشكرك على قبول مقابلتي يا سيد "شوفالد".‬
Dispense with the pointless pleasantries. I don't have time for them.
‫اعفني من المجاملات التي لا طائل منها.‬ ‫ليس لديّ وقت لهذا.‬
Tell me what you're here for.
‫أخبرني بسبب مجيئك إلى هنا.‬
I don't have much time either.
‫ليس لديّ وقت أنا أيضًا.‬
But whether or not this conversation ends quickly depends on you.
‫لكن مدة الحوار الذي سيدور بيننا‬ ‫مرهونة بك أنت.‬
Did you come to talk about him?
‫هل أتيت للتحدث عنه؟‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
I mean Johan.
‫أعني "يوهان".‬
It seems I was right.
‫يبدو أنني كنت محقًا.‬
I figured that someday someone like you would come to me.
‫خطر لي أن شخصًا مثلك قد يزورني.‬
You've come to solve the mystery.
‫أتيت لحلّ اللغز.‬
"Mystery?"
‫لغز؟‬
That boy is far too perfect.
‫ذلك الفتى مثالي إلى حد لا يُصدق.‬
People who can see probably cannot tell. But I can sense it.
‫المبصرون يعجزون عن تبيّن ذلك على الأرجح.‬ ‫لكن يسعني الشعور بذلك.‬
I can tell I'm in the presence of someone so utterly perfect.
‫يمكنني تبيّن أن ثمة شخص مثالي تمامًا.‬
I can sense that he's not of this world at all.
‫أشعر بأنه ليس من عالمنا.‬
No, he's very much of this world.
‫بل إنه من عالمنا بلا شك.‬
It's all written right here, a sample of his past.
‫كُتبت كل التفاصيل هنا. إنها عينة من ماضيه.‬
I'll read it to you and you'll see that he's not some sort of illusion.
‫سأقرأها لك وسترى أنه ليس وهمًا.‬
"It started in 1986 when a young boy
‫"بدأت الأحداث في عام 1986‬
was taken to a hospital with a near -fatal injury."
‫عندما نُقل صبي إلى مستشفى‬ ‫بإصابة شبه قاتلة."‬
And then he came to you.
‫ثم قصدك.‬
My dead… No, my murdered friend, Richard, had a theory.
‫صديقي الميت… بل المقتول، "ريتشارد"،‬ ‫كان قد توصل إلى نظرية.‬
He believed it was Johan who had Fahren pretend to be your son.
‫كان يظن أن "يوهان"‬ ‫من دفع "فاهرين" للادعاء بأنه ابنك.‬
But then the minute your real son, Karl, showed up,
‫لكن في اللحظة‬ ‫التي ظهر فيها ابنك الحقيقي "كارل"،‬
he changed his plans and latched onto him.
‫غيّر خططه وتقرّب منه.‬
Then he had Fahren kill himself.
‫وعندئذ دفع "فاهرين" إلى قتل نفسه.‬
Why did you allow yourself to be reunited with your long-lost son?
‫لم سمحت بأن يُعاد شملك بابنك‬ ‫الذي فقدته منذ سنوات؟‬
How many people that you've been close to died these past few years?
‫كم مات من المقربين إليك‬ ‫في السنوات القليلة الماضية؟‬
Your driver of many years.
‫سائقك قبل عدة سنوات.‬
The maid who read to you.
‫خادمتك التي تقرأ لك.‬
The accountant you went bird-watching with.
‫المحاسب الذي كنت تراقب الطيور معه.‬
They're all dead now.
‫ماتوا جميعهم.‬
Johan murdered them all to isolate you.
‫قتلهم "يوهان" ليعزلك.‬
Then he'd fill the emptiness you felt himself.
‫ثم ملأ هو ما شعرت به من خواء.‬
Please, I want you to help me. We'll expose him for everything he's done!
‫أريدك أن تساعدني من فضلك. سنكشف كل أفعاله.‬
Unless we do that now, the Japanese doctor, Dr. Tenma, he'll…
‫إن لم نفعل ذلك الآن،‬ ‫فالطبيب الياباني د. "تينما" سوف…‬
You said that Johan is playing as if he's messing with a line of ants.
‫أتقول إن "يوهان" يتبع منهجية‬ ‫زعزعة صف النمل.‬
Yes.
‫أجل.‬
A line of ants, eh?
‫صف النمل؟‬
Do you know what people call me?
‫أتعرف بما يلقبونني الناس؟‬
I'm called the Vampire of Bavaria.
‫أُلقب بمصاص دماء "بافاريا".‬
I took pride in being called that.
‫أتفاخر بهذا اللقب.‬
The more I pursued my interests, the larger it became…
‫كلما اجتهدت في تحقيق مصالحي، يتضخم…‬
the monster inside me.
‫الوحش الذي بداخلي.‬
But look at me now.
‫لكن تأمل حالي الآن.‬
My nickname is impressive, but I'm a withered old man now.
‫لقبي مبهر ولكنني مسنّ ضعيف.‬
When I think about it, I too wanted to mess with that line of ants as well…
‫عند التفكير في تلك المسألة،‬ ‫أجد أنني أردت زعزعة صف النمل أيضًا…‬
in this same way.
‫بمثل تلك الطريقة.‬
I can see that he is trying to become that person I wanted to be.
‫أرى أنه أراد‬ ‫أن يصبح الشخص الذي أردت أن أكونه.‬
“Who is like the beast?
‫"من الذي يشبه الوحش؟‬
Who can wage war against it?”
‫من الذي يسعه أن يشن حربًا عليه؟"‬
The Book of Revelation, right?
‫"سفر الرؤيا"، أليس كذلك؟‬
The only thing that can defeat the beast
‫الوحيد الذي يسعه هزيمة الوحش‬
is another even more ferocious beast.
‫هو وحش آخر أشد شراسة منه.‬
Father.
‫أبي.‬
Yes?
‫نعم؟‬
What were you talking to him about? You were up all night.
‫عمّ كنت تتحدث إليه؟ بقيت ساهرًا طوال الليل.‬
Tell me, where's Johan?
‫أين "يوهان"؟‬
He said he'll be going directly to the ceremony
‫قال إنه سيتجه إلى الحفل مباشرةً‬
after he's done at the Esterhofen office.
‫بعد الانتهاء من العمل في فرع "إسترهوفن".‬
Father, you look quite tired.
‫تبدو متعبًا يا أبي.‬
Maybe we should cancel today's ceremony.
‫لعلّه يجدر بك أن تلغي حفل اليوم.‬
No, let's get ready to attend.
‫لا، لنستعد لحضوره.‬
Kill… him…
‫اقتليه…‬
Dr. Tenma, it's not your fault.
‫لست المذنب يا دكتور "تينما".‬
You only did your job as a doctor.
‫أدّيت واجبك بصفتك طبيبًا.‬
You're not to blame.
‫لست الملام على ذلك.‬
Please live on.
‫انج بحياتك من فضلك.‬
And save as many people as you can.
‫وأنقذ أكبر عدد من الناس يمكنك إنقاذه.‬
Nina…
‫"نينا"…‬
That's a real shame.
‫كم هذا مؤسف.‬
Are you calling it quits?
‫ستتركين العمل؟‬
But you'd only just gotten used to the work.
‫لكنك اعتدت للتو على العمل.‬
I really appreciate all you've done.
‫أنا ممتنة حقًا على كل ما فعلته.‬
If you're ever back this way, contact me.
‫إن عدت إلى إلى هذه المنطقة، فتواصلي معي.‬
I will. Goodbye.
‫سأفعل. مع السلامة.‬
She was such a pleasant girl too.
‫ما ألطفها من فتاة.‬
Hello? Is Lotte Frank there?
‫مرحبًا؟ هل "لوتي فرانك" موجودة؟‬
Lotte is out right now.
‫"لوتي" في الخارج حاليًا.‬
I see. Can you send her a message?
‫مفهوم. هلّا تبلغيها برسالة.‬
Please tell her I'll be leaving Munich on the 3 p.m. train.
‫أخبريها من فضلك بأنني سأرحل عن "ميونخ"‬ ‫في قطار الثالثة عصرًا.‬
All right. I'll tell her. Oh, may I have your name again?
‫حسنًا. سأخبرها. هلّا تخبرينني باسمك مجددًا.‬
It's Nina.
‫اسمي "نينا".‬
Nina Fortner.
‫"نينا فورتنر".‬
He's arrived. His car arrived at the back entrance.
‫وصل. وصلت سيارته إلى المدخل الخلفي.‬
At last, the Vampire of Bavaria has arrived.
‫وصل أخيرًا مصاص دماء "بافاريا".‬
He'll hear you.
‫سيسمعك.‬
You've seen who's here, haven't you?
‫رأيت من حضر، أليس كذلك؟‬
Of course. There are big shots here not just from Bavaria but from businesses
‫بالتأكيد. ثمة الكثير من الشخصيات المهمة‬ ‫هنا، ليس من "بافاريا" فحسب بل ومن شركات‬
all over Europe and Japan, as well as diplomats and politicians.
‫من كافة أرجاء "أوروبا" و"اليابان"،‬ ‫إلى جانب دبلوماسيين وسياسيين.‬
It's hard to believe this is just a library book donation ceremony.
‫يصعب تصديق أن هذا مجرد حفل‬ ‫للتبرع بكتب لمكتبة.‬
They do say that every move that Mr. Schuwald makes
‫يُقال إن كل خطوة يتخذها السيد "شوفالد"‬
affects all the economies of Europe.
‫تؤثّر على اقتصاد "أوروبا".‬
He seldom appears in public.
‫نادرًا ما يظهر في العلن.‬
It's no wonder there's such a huge crowd.
‫لا عجب في أن الحشد هائل.‬
But this sudden donation of his collection,
‫لكن ألا يبدو هذا التبرع المفاجئ لمجموعته‬
doesn't it seem like a parting gift?
‫كهدية فراق؟‬
Hey, don't talk like that.
‫إياك وقول كلام من هذا القبيل.‬
He's the cornerstone of the EU economy.
‫إنه حجر الأساس لاقتصاد الاتحاد الأوروبي.‬
He can't call it quits just yet.
‫لا يمكنه التوقف بعد.‬
Karl.
‫"كارل".‬
Yes?
‫نعم؟‬
I forgot some papers. I'd like you to go and get them.
‫ثمة أوراق نسيتها. أريدك أن تذهب لإحضارها.‬
What papers?
‫أي أوراق؟‬
Just go to the estate and get them. They're on the desk in my study.
‫اذهب لإحضارها. ستجدها على طاولة مكتبي.‬
But Father…
‫لكن يا أبي…‬
Johan will be here soon. Leave the rest of this to him.
‫سيصل "يوهان" بعد قليل.‬ ‫سيتولى ما بقي من إجراءات.‬
All right.
‫حسنًا.‬
What on earth is happening with the investigation?
‫كيف تسير التحقيقات؟‬
It's progressing nicely.
‫تسير على أكمل وجه.‬
"Progressing nicely?"
‫"تسير على أكمل وجه"؟‬
I told you Tenma was here in Munich because I believed you would
‫أخبرتك بأن "تينما" هنا في "ميونخ"‬ ‫لأنني حسبتك‬
carry on the investigation seriously.
‫ستجري التحريات بجدية.‬
But you haven't done a thing!
‫لكنك لم تفعل شيئًا!‬
Have you investigated Schuwald's secretary, Johan Liebert?
‫هل تحرّيت عن سكرتير "شوفالد"،‬ ‫"يوهان ليبرت"؟‬
He is without a doubt the person behind all these murders!
‫هو المسؤول عن كل جرائم القتل بالتأكيد!‬
Are you even listening?
‫هل تنصت إليّ حتى؟‬
If you don't do something…
‫إن لم تفعل شيئًا…‬
Tenma will try to end this all by his hand!
‫سيحاول "تيمنا" أن ينهي المسألة بنفسه!‬
Not to worry.
‫لا تقلق.‬
The investigation is truly progressing smoothly.
‫تسير التحقيقات على أكمل وجه حقًا.‬
Goodbye.
‫مع السلامة.‬
Johan exists! He's right here! You've got to stop him!
‫"يوهان" موجود فعلًا! إنه هنا! يجب أن توقفه!‬
The words of a true criminal psychologist.
‫ينم كلامك عن أنك طبيب نفسي ضليع.‬
You're quite right about that.
‫أنت محق في رأيك هذا.‬
There's no doubt that Johan exists.
‫لا شك في أن لـ"يوهان" وجودًا.‬
Johan exists…
‫"يوهان" موجود…‬
in Tenma's head.
‫في مخيّلة "تينما".‬
Have you gotten anything else out of him?
‫هل عرفت منه أي معلومة أخرى؟‬
No. It's just the same old story over and over again.
‫لا. إنها القصة القديمة ذاتها تتكرر دائمًا.‬
The rifle is a Mauser SR93.
‫البندقية طراز "ماوزر إس آر 93".‬
He sold it to a Japanese guy.
‫باعها لرجل ياباني.‬
Want us to squeeze him for more?
‫أتريدنا أن نضغط عليه لمعرفة المزيد؟‬
No, that's probably all that he knows.
‫لا، هذا كلّ ما يعرفه على الأرجح.‬
Okay.
‫حسنًا.‬
Isn't a Mauser SR93 a sniper rifle?
‫أليست بندقية "ماوزر إس آر 93"، بندقية قنص؟‬
That's right. A high-precision one.
‫هذا صحيح وهي عالية الدقة.‬
Who the heck could he be going after with that?
‫بمن يتربص يا ترى؟‬
I am Tenma.
‫أنا "تينما".‬
I have acquired a high-precision sniper rifle.
‫حصلت على بندقية قنص عالية الدقة.‬
And I am…
‫وأنا…‬
I am Johan.
‫أنا "يوهان".‬
Who would I shoot with this gun?
‫من قد أقتل بهذه البندقية؟‬
I killed the hospital director and those others.
‫قتلت مدير المستشفى والآخرين.‬
I killed many middle-aged couples.
‫قتلت عدة أزواج في منتصف أعمارهم.‬
And who will I kill now?
‫فمن سأقتل الآن؟‬
I am… chaos.
‫أنا أمثّل الفوضى.‬
I enjoy chaos.
‫أستمتع بالفوضى.‬
You should eat something.
‫يجب أن تأكل.‬
You're right. Thanks, Dieter.
‫أنت محق. أشكرك يا "ديتر".‬
I'll be fine. Don't worry about me.
‫سأكون بخير. لا تقلق عليّ.‬
It'll take more than this to make me give up.
‫سيتطلب الأمر ما هو أكثر من ذلك لأستسلم.‬
I may not look like it, but when I was a medic for the border guard,
‫قد لا يدل مظهري على ذلك‬ ‫ولكنني عندما كنت مسعفًا في حرس الحدود،‬
I trained hard both physically and mentally.
‫خضت تدريبات شاقة بدنيًا وذهنيًا.‬
I'll do whatever it takes to save your friend. Whatever it takes!
‫سأفعل كلّ ما يتطلبه الأمر لأنقذ صديقك.‬ ‫مهما تطلب الأمر.‬
Don't underestimate an ex-police medic.
‫لا تستهن بمسعف سابق كان يعمل لدى الشرطة.‬
Now, since you've prepared this wonderful meal, Dieter,
‫بما أنك من أعددت‬ ‫هذه الوجبة الشهية يا "ديتر"،‬
I'd better dig in.
‫فيُستحسن بي أن آكلها.‬
You can't fight on an empty stomach, you know.
‫لا يستطيع أن يناضل المرء بمعدة خاوية.‬
This is it!
‫هذه هي!‬
Did you find anything?
‫أثمة ما وجدته؟‬
It's Schuwald's book donation ceremony!
‫إنه حفل "شوفالد" للتبرع بالكتب.‬
Do you think Tenma's there?
‫أتظن أن "تينما" هناك؟‬
You stay here, Dieter!
‫ابق أنت هنا يا "ديتر"!‬
Don't follow me!
‫لا تلحق بي!‬
It's Schuwald.
‫إنه "شوفالد".‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
I want to speak with Hans Georg Schuwald. Contact him.
‫أريد التحدث إلى "هانس جورج شوفالد".‬ ‫اتصل به.‬
Okay.
‫حسنًا.‬
Wait. If I'm not mistaken, he'll be at the Munich University Library
‫مهلًا. لو لم أكن مخطئًا،‬ ‫فإنه في مكتبة جامعة "ميونخ"‬
for a book donation ceremony.
‫لحضور حفل التبرع بالكتب.‬
-Send men there immediately. -What?
‫- أرسل رجالًا إلى هناك في الحال.‬ ‫- ماذا؟‬
It's Schuwald that Tenma's after.
‫"شوفالد" هو من يسعى "تينما" لقتله.‬
Let us now honor the man who is making this generous donation to our library.
‫لنكرّم الرجل‬ ‫الذي يقدّم هذا التبرع السخي لمكتبتنا.‬
Please give a warm welcome to Mr. Hans Georg Schuwald.
‫رحبّوا بحفاوة من فضلكم‬ ‫بالسيد "هانس جورج شوفالد".‬
Where's Johan?
‫أين "يوهان"؟‬
Is my secretary here?
‫هل سكرتيري هنا؟‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
Ah, he's over there.
‫إنه هناك.‬
So, he's come.
‫لقد أتى.‬
I brought him back to life.
‫أنا من أعدته إلى الحياة.‬
I brought that monster back to life.
‫أنا من أعدت هذا الوحش إلى الحياة.‬
Nina!
‫"نينا"!‬
Lotte! You came!
‫"لوتي"! لقد أتيت!‬
I'm sorry. I searched a lot for the person I'm looking for,
‫أنا آسفة. بحثت كثيرًا عن الشخص‬ ‫الذي أبحث عنه،‬
but I doubt I'll find him here.
‫لكنني أشك في أن أعثر عليه هنا.‬
We were just getting to be friends too. It's a shame.
‫كانت صداقتنا قد نشأت لتوّها للأسف.‬
You two are twins, aren't you?
‫أنتما توأم، أليس كذلك؟‬
You are, aren't you? Aren't you?
‫ألستما كذلك؟‬
What's with this picture book?
‫ما قصة الكتاب المصوّر هذا؟‬
He suddenly fainted when he saw this!
‫فقد وعيه فجأة ما إن رآه!‬
A picture book?
‫كتاب مصوّر؟‬
Kill him…
‫اقتليه…‬